Register of the Ignace Jan Paderewski papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1894-1941 (Boxes 2-5)
  - Smulski, Jan F. and Mrs., 1921?-1928 (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - Sobanski, Wladyslaw, 1923-1940 (Box-folder 5: 21)
    Includes correspondence with Piotr Drzewiecki and Prince Sapieha, and memoranda on conditions in occupied Poland.
  - Sokal, Mr. and Mrs., 1929 (Box-folder 5: 22)
  - Southam, Herbert, undated (Box-folder 5: 23)
  - Speyer, James, 1923-1936 (Box-folder 5: 24)
  - Sroczynski, undated (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - Stapp, Philipp B., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - Starzynski, Stefan, 1936 (Box-folder 5: 27)
  - Steinway family, 1924-1929 (Box-folder 5: 28)
    Includes correspondence with Edwin B. Orcutt.
  - Stojowski, Mr. and Mrs., 1922-1925 (Box-folder 5: 29)
  - Stowarzyszenie Kupcow Polskich w Stanach Zjednoczonych, 1941 (Box-folder 5: 30)
  - Strakacz, Sylwin, 1924-1926 (Box-folder 5: 31)
  - Stronski, Stanislaw, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 5: 32)
  - Swiecicki, J.? A., undated (Box-folder 5: 33)
  - Szajnert, Juliusz, 1921 or 1922 (Box-folder 5: 34)
  - Szaniawski, A. F., 1925 (Box-folder 5: 35)
  - Szlagowski, Antoni, 1929 (Box-folder 5: 36)
  - Szopinski, D., 1928 (Box-folder 5: 37)
  - Szyller, Mr., 1924 (Box-folder 5: 38)
  - Tadlewski, 1929 (Box-folder 5: 39)
  - Tardieu, Andre, undated (Box-folder 5: 40)
  - Tavern Club (Boston), undated (Box-folder 5: 41)
  - Tedeschini, Monsignor, undated (Box-folder 5: 42)
  - Teodorowicz, Archbishop, undated (Box-folder 5: 43)
  - Times, The (Los Angeles), 1922 (Box-folder 5: 44)
  - Titulescu, N., 1925 (Box-folder 5: 45)
  - Tomkowski, 1941 (Box-folder 5: 46)
  - Tremaine, Mr. (Aeolian Company), 1929 (Box-folder 5: 47)
  - Treowen, Lord, 1925 (Box-folder 5: 48)
  - Tucker, Mona House, 1923 (Box-folder 5: 49)
  - Tymieniecki, Bishop, 1931 (Box-folder 5: 50)
  - University of Glasgow (Mr. Bayne; Sir Donald MacAlister; G. Milligan), 1925-1934 (Box-folder 5: 51)
    Includes letter to Hugh Ryan.
  - University of Poznan, 1936 (Box-folder 5: 52)
  - Uniwersytet Jagiellonski (Krakow) (Zdzislaw Jachimecki; Rostworowski), 1925 (Box-folder 5: 53)
  - Urchs, Emma and Ernest, 1923-1928 (Box-folder 5: 54)
  - Usher, Mr., 1926 (Box-folder 5: 55)
  - Valloben?, 1934 (Box-folder 5: 56)
  - Vallotton, Henry, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 5: 57)
  - Van der Stucken, Frank, 1928 (Box-folder 5: 58)
  - Vanderbilt, George, Mrs., 1923 (Box-folder 5: 59)
  - Vaulx, Foulon de, Mrs., 1924?-1926 (Box-folder 5: 60)
  - Vaxelaire, Max, 1940 (Box-folder 5: 61)
  - Vendome, Duchesse de, 1939 (Box-folder 5: 62)
  - Venizelos, Eleutherios, 1921-1928 (Box-folder 5: 63)
  - Wade, H. H., 1939 (Box-folder 5: 64)
  - Walcott, Frederick, 1928 (Box-folder 5: 65)
  - Wander, Eugene, 1923-1925 (Box-folder 5: 66)
  - Warszawskie Towarzystwo Muzyczne, 1894 (Box-folder 5: 67)
  - Wedel, Baron de, 1925 (Box-folder 5: 68)
  - Weld, George Francis, 1922 (Box-folder 5: 69)
  - Weygand, Maxime, 1920-1940 (Box-folder 5: 70)
  - Wiadomosci Literackie, 1935 (Box-folder 5: 71)
  - Wieckowski, Jan, undated (Box-folder 5: 72)
  - Wieniawski, Adam, 1925 (Box-folder 5: 73)
  - Wilcox, Captain, 1925 (Box-folder 5: 74)
  - Wilson, Woodrow and Mrs., 1914-1924 (Box-folder 5: 75)
  - Witkowski, Edward S., 1935-1936 (Box-folder 5: 76)
  - Witos, Wincenty, 1936 (Box-folder 5: 77)
  - Wojtalewicz, Reverend, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 5: 78)
  - Wolowska, H. B., 1941 (Box-folder 5: 79)
  - Woods, Arthur and Helen, undated (Box-folder 5: 80)
  - World, The (New York), 1923 (Box-folder 5: 81)
  - Wroblewski, A., 1923-1924 (Box-folder 5: 82)
  - Wurzburger, Alexander, 1924 (Box-folder 5: 83)
  - Zaleski, August, 1939 (Box-folder 5: 84)
  - Zamoyski, Adam, 1924-1928? (Box-folder 5: 85)
  - Zawadzki, Wladyslaw, 1927? (Box-folder 5: 86)
  - Zeissler, Fannie, 1925 (Box-folder 5: 87)
  - Zgorzelscy, Jozef and Maria, 1935 (Box-folder 5: 88)
  - Zjednoczenie Polskie Rzymsko Katolickie (Stanley Adamkiewicz; Stefanowicz), 1924?-1926 (Box-folder 5: 89)
  - Zulonga, Ignacio, undated (Box-folder 5: 90)
  - Zwiazek Narodowy Polski (M. Blenski, J. Magdziarz Skarbnik, Kazimierz Zychlinski), 1921-1924 (Box-folder 5: 91)
  - Zwiazek Ziemian Powiatu Wegrowskiego, 1929 (Box-folder 5: 92)
  - Zychlinska, Mrs., 1934 (Box-folder 5: 93)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1910-1941 (Boxes 6-8)
  Dedications, essays, messages, notes, open letters, speeches, tributes, and writings, arranged chronologically by title.
  - Untitled essays and notes, including on the history of Polish merchants, Polish politics, literature, and jazz, undated (Box-folder 6: 1)
    Includes dedication on funeral wreath for Mr. Venizelos. Holograph (in Polish, French, and English).
  - Message from Riond-Bosson, Switzerland, to Polish Americans, typescript (in Polish), undated (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Message from Rochester, New York, to volunteer officers and soldiers of the Polish Army in the United States, typescript (in Polish), undated (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Message upon the anniversary of the Wielkopolskie uprising, typescript telegram (in Polish), undated (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Speech, Geneva, Switzerland, holograph (in French), undated (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Speech honoring Jan Ciechanowski, France, holograph and typescript (in Polish), undated (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Speech on the occasion of the unveiling of the John Ruskin Monument, Chamonix, France, holograph and typescript (in French and English), undated (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Speech, Polish Sejm, holograph (in Polish), undated (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Speech upon receiving the honorary citizenship of the towns of Vevey and Morges, Switzerland, holograph (in French), undated (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Speech upon receiving the honorary citizenship of the town of Tolochanaz, holograph and typescript (in French), undated (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Speech, Venice City Hall, holograph and typescript (in French), undated (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Speeches upon conferring, on behalf of the President of Poland, Polish decorations on Americans and Polish Americans, Chicago and New York, undated (Box-folder 6: 12-14)
    Includes correspondence and lists. Holograph and typescript (in Polish and English).
  - "Tempo Rubato," holograph (in English), undated (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Message to Polish Merchants' Convention, Krakow, Poland, holograph (in Polish), 1910? (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Speech, Chopin Centenary Festival, Lvov, Poland, holograph and printed copy (in Polish) and printed copy of English translation by Laurence Alma Tadema, 1910 October 23 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - Speech to Polish Americans, holograph (in Polish), 1915 May 27 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - "Poland: Past and Present," speech, Polish Benefit Concert, Chicago, Illinois, printed copy, 1916 February 5 (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - Speech after the Act of 1916 November 5, holograph (in Polish), circa 1916 November 5 (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Speech upon the death of Henryk Sienkiewicz, Chicago, Illinois, printed copy (in Polish), 1916 November 27 (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - "Remarks on Poland," speech, Teachers' College, Columbia University, New York City, printed copy, 1917 May (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - Speech, Polish Army in the United States, holograph (in Polish), 1917 October 6 (Box-folder 6: 23)
  - Speech, Liga Narodow, Geneva, Switzerland, typescript (in French), 1919? (Box-folder 6: 24)
  - Speech, opening meeting of the Polish Council of Ministers, Warsaw, Poland, holograph (in Polish), 1919 January 14 (Box-folder 6: 25)
  - Speech, third meeting of the Polish Constituent Sejm, typescript (in Polish), 1919 February 2 (Box-folder 6: 26)
  - Speeches, 10th, 18th, 40th, 81st, and 97th sessions of the Polish Sejm, printed copy of official record (in Polish), 1919 March 5 - November 12 (Box-folder 6: 27)
  - Speeches, 9th session of the Council of the League of Nations, Paris, printed copy of official record (in French and English), 1920 September 16-20 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Speeches, 11th session of the Council of the League of Nations, Paris, printed copy of official record (in French and English), 1920 November 14 - December 18 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Speeches, 5th, 13th, 15th, and 27th plenary meetings of the League of Nations, Paris, typescript excerpts of minutes (in French and English), 1920 November 17 - December 16 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Speech, Century Club, Boston, holograph and typescript (in English), 1921? (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Speech, Chicago, Illinois, holograph (in Polish), 1922? (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Tribute to Pope Pius XI after his accession to the pontifical throne, typescript statement from Paso Robles to the United Press (in English), 1922 February 8 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Speech, Woodrow Wilson memorial, holograph (in English), 1924 March? (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - Speech on the occasion of the transfer of Henryk Sienkiewicz's ashes to Poland, Vevey, Switzerland, printed copy (in French), 1924 October 24 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Notes on Polish politics, holograph (in Polish), 1924 November (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Speech, Poznan High School, holograph and typescript (in Polish), 1924 November (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Speech, Poznan University, Poland, holograph, typescript, and correspondence (in Polish), 1924 November (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Speech, reception given by President and Mrs. Cyryl Ratajski, Poznan, holograph and typescript (in Polish), 1924 November (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - Speech upon receiving the honorary citizenship of Poznan, Poland, holograph and typescript (in Polish), 1924 November (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - Speech, Poznan City Hall, holograph and typescript (in Polish), 1924 November 24 (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - Speech at Katowice railroad station en route to Poznan, holograph and typescript (in Polish), 1925 (Box-folder 7: 15)
  - Speech, League of Nations banquet, Geneva, Switzerland, holograph (in French), 1925 (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - Speech, Polish delegation to the League of Nations banquet, Geneva, holograph (in French), 1925 (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - Speech upon receiving the honorary citizenship of Lausanne, Switzerland, holograph (in French), 1925 (Box-folder 7: 18)
  - Speech, London Press Club, holograph, typescript, and correspondence (in English), 1925 July 13 (Box-folder 7: 19)
  - Speech, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, holograph (in Polish), 1926 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Speech, Conseil Communal de Morges, Switzerland, holograph and typescript (in French), 1926 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Speech, 150th anniversary of the Declaration of Independence of the United States of America, Paris, holograph (in English), 1926 July (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - Message to the Polish Association in Sydney, Australia, holograph, typescript, and correspondence (in Polish), 1927 April 15 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Speech, American Legion, holograph and typescript (in English), 1928 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Speech commemorating Jan F. Smulski, Chicago, Illinois, holograph and typescript (in Polish and English), 1928 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Speech, Kosciuszko Foundation, New York City, holograph and typescript (in English), 1928 May 16 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Open letter to Senator Borah, typescript (in English), 1931 November 30 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - "Poland and Peace," speech broadcast by NBC, American Polish Chamber of Commerce, Civic Forum, and Council on Foreign Relations, New York City, 1932 May 18 (Box-folder 8: 9)
    Holograph, typescript, and printed copy (in English) and printed copy of French translation. Includes invitation from the Council on Foreign Relations.
  - "Poland's So-Called Corridor," Foreign Affairs, printed copy, 1933 April (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Preface to Charlotte Kellogg, Mrs. Jadwiga, Queen of Poland, holograph and correspondence with Charlotte Kellogg, 1933 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - Introduction to the home publication of Colonel Snively's letters to his family during World War I, holograph, typescript, and correspondence with Marjorie K. Snively, 1933 November? (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Speech honoring Bishop Besson, Riond-Bosson, Switzerland, holograph (in French), 1934 June 10 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - Speech honoring the Marquis de St. Paul, French Embassy, Bern, Switzerland, holograph (in French), 1934 August 14 (Box-folder 8: 14)
  - Speech honoring Anna de Noailles, Evian, France, holograph, 1935 August 25 (Box-folder 8: 15)
  - Statement sent to the editor of a Polish publication asking him not to make a fuss over his birthday, typescript (in Polish), 1935 September 30 (Box-folder 8: 16)
  - Two essays or letters on Silesia, holograph (one in Polish and one in English), 1936 (Box-folder 8: 17)
  - Essay on Polish internal politics, typescript (in Polish), 1937 August 26 (Box-folder 8: 18)
  - Message from Riond-Bosson to the Polish Democratic Christian Congress and the National Workers Party, typescript (in Polish), 1937 October 3 (Box-folder 8: 19)
  - The Paderewski Memoirs (with Mary Lawton), holograph fragment and correspondence with Mary Lawton, 1938 (Box-folder 8: 20)
  - Statement in response to Jozef Beck's speech regarding German demands, typescript (in Polish), 1939 (Box-folder 8: 21)
  - Statement on Danzig, typescript and correspondence with Associated Press (in French), 1939 August (Box-folder 8: 22)
  - Message to the American people, typescript (in English), 1939 August 30 (Box-folder 8: 23)
  - Message to Polish émigrés in France, holograph and typescript (in Polish), 1939 September (Box-folder 8: 24)
  - Message to Polish Americans, typescript (in Polish), 1939 September (Box-folder 8: 25)
  - Message to the Swiss people, typescript (in French), 1939 September 23 (Box-folder 8: 26)
  - Message to Polish émigrés in France, holograph and typescript (in Polish), 1939 October 18 (Box-folder 8: 27)
  - Message to Wrarus Polski (Polish veterans organization), typescript (in Polish), 1939 December 31 (Box-folder 8: 28)
  - Message to the American people, NBC Radio, typescript (in English and Polish), 1940 April 16 (Box-folder 8: 29)
  - Message to the French people, Radio Francaise, typescript (in French and Polish), 1940 May 3 (Box-folder 8: 30)
  - Message to Poles in Poland, typescript (in Polish), 1940 May 31 (Box-folder 8: 31)
  - Message to the soldiers of the Polish Army's 2nd Division, interned in Switzerland, typescript (in Polish), 1940 August 22 (Box-folder 8: 32)
  - Message to the Swiss people upon departure for the United States, typescript (in French), 1940 September 12 (Box-folder 8: 33)
  - Statement aboard S.S. Excambion upon arrival in New York, typescript (in English), 1940 November 6 (Box-folder 8: 34)
  - Message to Polish Americans, typescript (in Polish), 1940 November 6 (Box-folder 8: 35)
    Includes typescript of publication in Dziennik Zwiazkowy, Chicago, 1940 November 7.
  - Message to the American people, holograph and typescript (in English), 1940 November 6 (Box-folder 8: 36)
  - Message to the British people, Reuter's, typescript (in English), 1940 November 6 (Box-folder 8: 37)
    Includes typescript of Polish translation published in Dziennik Zwiazkowy, Chicago, 1940 November 19.
  - Radio broadcast upon his 80th birthday, asking for contributions to the Paderewski Testimonial Fund, typescript (in English), 1940 November 6 (Box-folder 8: 38)
  - Discussion with Marshall E. Dimock (Immigration and Naturalization Service), CBS Radio, typescript (in English), 1940 December 8 (Box-folder 8: 39)
  - Message to Polish Americans (first page missing), typescript (in Polish), 1940 December 25 (Box-folder 8: 40)
  - Message to veterans of the Polish Army in the United States, typescript (in Polish), 1941 March 28 (Box-folder 8: 41)
  - Message to be read by Sylwin Strakacz, Zjazd Homiletyczny, Detroit, Michigan, typescript (in Polish), 1941 April 21 (Box-folder 8: 42)
  - Speech, Polish Veterans Association Convention, Oak Ridge, New Jersey, typescript (in Polish), 1941 June 22 (Box-folder 8: 43)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1687-1948 (Box 9)
  Appeals, certificate, correspondence, drawings, eulogies, letters of recommendation, minutes of meetings, newsletters, speeches, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Gdansk. Curicken, Rheinhold, Beschreibung der Stadt Danzig, 1687 (Box-folder 9: 1)
    Contains annotations through 1842 by subsequent mayors of Danzig.
  - Jakobkiewicz, Joseph. Paderewski's letter of recommendation, 1921 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - Kazimierz III, King of Poland, 1310-1390. Vatican certificate authenticating bones of Casimir the Great (in Latin), 1905 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - Korfanty, Wojciech. Printed eulogy by Izydor Modelski and J. Malinowski, 1939 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Kwapiszewski, Michal. Paderewski's letter of recommendation, 1935 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Modjeska, Helena
    - Bound notebook containing text of Acts III and IV of Adrienne Lecouvreur in Modjeska's handwriting, undated (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - Drawings of stage costumes for Modjeska by W. T. Benda, annotated by Modjeska, 1899 (Box-folder 9: 7)
    - Miscellany holograph items and clippings, 1871-1890? (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - Noailles, Anna de. Correspondence of Paderewski with various relatives of the Countess, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 9: 9)
    Including Constantin Bracoveanu, and others relating to the commemorative ceremony in Evian, 1935; with the Syndic of Vevey relating to another commemorative ceremony, 1936; and with the Societe des Amis et Admirateurs d'Anna de Noailles, 1935.
  - Paderewski Testimonial Fund. Newsletters, press releases, and correspondence, including between Paderewski and Charlotte Kellogg, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 9: 10)
    Includes correspondence and minutes of meetings of the Kosciuszko Foundation, Polish Falcons of America, and Rada Polonii Amerykanskiej.
  - Prisoners of war - Poland. Correspondence of Paderewski with Polish soldiers interned in Switzerland, and with General Prugar-Kettling, General Henri Guisan, and Colonel Henry Vallotton, 1940 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - Pro Polonia. Newsletters and appeal (1939-1942) (in French); and correspondence (1939-1940) of Paderewski regarding contributions, including with Mrs. Foch (Box-folder 9: 12)
    Includes appeal by Aide Suisse aux Prisonniers de Guerre Polonais.
  - Rada Polonii Amerykanskiej. Correspondence of Paderewski, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 9: 13)
    Including with Francis X. Swietlik, 1940-1941; letter from Maurice Pate to Swietlik, 1941; and diplomatic correspondence, 1941 (in Polish).
  - Sikorski, Wladyslaw. Correspondence, minutes of meetings, notes, speeches (in English and Polish), 1940-1941 (Box-folder 9: 14)
    Includes transcript of discussion with Sumner Welles.
  - Strakacz, Sylwin. Correspondence
    - General, 1941-1948 (Box-folder 9: 15)
    - Sikorski, Wladyslaw, 1936-1939 (Box-folder 9: 16)
      Includes a letter from Strakacz to Marshal Gamelin.
  - Tadema, Laurence Alma. Letters to Antonina Wilkonska, 1926-1939 (Box-folder 9: 17)
  - United States - Foreign relations - Poland. Radiogram from Robert Lansing to Paderewski communicating de iure recognition of Poland by the United States; and holograph letter from Paderewski to Lansing, 1919 January 26, undated (Box-folder 9: 18)
- PRINTED MATTER, 1922-1966 (Box 10)
  Bulletins, clippings, newsletters, pamphlets, serial issues, and miscellany relating mainly to Paderewski and to Poland, particularly before and during World War II. In English, Polish, French, and Portuguese.
  - Undated (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - 1922-1940 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - 1941 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - 1942-1947 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - 1948 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - 1949-1966 (Box-folder 10: 6)
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1917 (Box 11)
  Charcoal drawing of Paderewski's head and shoulders by W. T. Benda.
- MEMORABILIA, undated (Memorabilia cabinet)
  Bust of Paderewski, and paperweight with his head in relief.
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1923-1945? (Photo file)
  126 prints and 6 postcards depicting Paderewski and others, atrocities committed in Poland during World War II, Polish children and soldiers, and miscellany.
  - One album containing 83 prints and 4 postcards, 1923-1941 (Album fA)
    Depicts Paderewski at various events and others, including Mr. and Mrs. Bagniewski, Jan Ciechanowski, King George VI, Mr. and Mrs. Gutowski, Monsignor Kaczynski, I. Kollupajlo-La Grange, Tommy Majewski, Stanislaw Mikolajczyk, Lily Pons, Wladyslaw Raczkiewicz, Eleanor Roosevelt, Wladyslaw Sikorski, Minister Stanczyk, Mrs. Edward T. Stotesbury, Aniela Strakacz, Sylwin Strakacz, Tadeusz Styka, Francis X. Swietlik, A. Syski, Antonina Wilkonska, Mr. and Mrs. Witkowski, and Adam Zamoyski, and scenes from his funeral at Arlington Cemetery, 1941 July 6. Includes prints depicting busts of Paderewski by Malvina Hoffman and N. Tregor.
  - 1 print depicting a portrait of Paderewski by Tadeusz Styka, 1939; 1 print depicting Paderewski with Wladyslaw Sikorski, 1941; 1 print and 2 postcards depicting lodgings of Polish soldiers interned in Switzerland during World War II, with Paderewski's portrait hung on the walls; and 2 miscellany prints, undated (Envelope B)
  - 30 prints depicting atrocities committed in Poland during World War II; 6 prints depicting Polish children being fed by the Commission for Polish Relief, Winter 1940-1941; 2 prints depicting Polish soldiers, including one being decorated by General Sikorski with the Virtuti Militari order, undated (Envelope C)
- MOTION PICTURE FILM, 1932 (Film shelf)
  Access
  Use copy available.
  The 35mm motion picture film contains several attempts at an interview with Paderewski, the Polish pianist, by Mieczysław Marchlewski, Poland's Consul General in New York, likely taking place in the Polish Consulate General at 233 Madison Avenue. The interview promotes Paderewski's appearance at the benefit for unemployed musicians in 1932. The concert was held on February 8, 1932 in Madison Square Garden in New York, so the date of the interview is probably late January or very early February 1932.